刚才那鬼东西是什么
What the hell was that thing?
就这么突然窜出来
It just appeared out of nowhere.
那尖叫
And that shriek?
把我吓得够呛
Scared the crap out of me.
是某种会飞的猴子?
Some kind of a flying monkey?
飞猴?  什么东西  外空间星球上的?
A flying monkey? what is this, planet of oz?
在我看来  说是飞  那东西更像是跳
To me, it appeared to be leaping rather than flying.
那真是见鬼豪跳了
That was one hell of a leap.
我只说那玩意儿看起来像只猴子
I said it looked like a monkey.
你知道的  有毛有臂有腿来着
You know, hair, arms, legs--
还有喙
And a beak.
那东西没喙
Didn't have a beak.
什么  看这里  我把它拍下来了
What? here, I uploaded it.
算你对了  总算看清那东西了
Oh. you know, that really clears things up.
你以为它长啥样  这东西想干掉我
What do you expect? it was trying to kill me.
那鬼东西到底是什么
What the hell is that thing?
可以派支生物小分队下去调查调查
Let's send a team of biologists down there,
让他们研究去
Let them figure it out.
对阿尔法基地来说可能是个好去处
Might be a good place for an alpha site.
这星球看起来挺适合的
The planet did seem suitable--
气候适宜  物资富饶  水源充沛
Good climate, abundant food and water.
当作一个异地据点  是最好不过的了
Excellent choice for an offworld base.
除了那些飞猴
Aside from the flying monkeys.
好了  罗德尼  我们回基地了
All right, we're coming into range, rodney.
罗德尼?
Rodney?
巨大能源脉冲
serious power spike.
这可奇怪了
That's strange.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
还不知道
I don't know.
这些读数简直乱套了
These readings are all screwy.
驾驶失控了
I just lost steering.
说真的?
Really?
推进舱不会自动收起
The drive pods won't retract.
想点办法
Do something.
不知道问题出哪  我也没办法
I could if I knew what the problem was.
罗德尼
Rodney...
等下
Just-- just hang on, hang on.
要是收缩不了...
Yeah, but, if those pods don't retract--
我知道  给我点时间
I know, I know, just give me a second!
我们没时间了
We don't have a second!
真见鬼
What the hell?
我们失去能源了
We just lost power.
好吧  大家最好坐稳了
All right, you'd better hold on.
还好
Okay, good.
还好  是我说错了  能源还在
Good! I was wrong, we still have power.
只是它既没供应上主系统
It's just not getting to any of the primary systems.
备用系统也没有
Or the secondary systems, either.
什么原因
Why not?
不晓得
I don't know,
处于某种干扰吧
It's some kind of interference.
供应不断的在波动
I'm getting spikes all over the place.
完全失控了
It's completely haywire.
幸好调节器未受影响
Thank god the inertial dampeners weren't affected.
只是还没有
Well, not yet.
上帝啊
Jeez!
刚才这下算什么
What the hell is that?
位移电流
Displacement current.
高压电!  最好避开
High voltage! do not let it hit you.
你说呢
Oh, you think?
可能是什么从星球上带上来的东西吧
Perhaps it's something we picked up on the planet.
这有待检查
That is doubtful, okay?
那儿没什么科技产物
There was nothing technological--
这星球没古人或其他什么的
I mean, ancient or other-- on that planet.
都是些原始生命
It was totally primordial.
星球磁层中没有探测到任何异样
I didn't detect anything unusual in the planet's magnetosphere.
我看  一定是飞船的电容器某处
Look, it's got to be some kind of glitch
出了小故障
In the jumper's capacitors.
给我点时间  我来看看问题出哪了
Just give me a second, I'll figure out how to--
又怎么了
What?
撞击星门减慢了我们的速度
Hitting the gate decreased our speed,
这意味我们现在在次轨道上
Which means we're in decaying orbit.
如果飞船不恢复能源动力
If we don't get power back,
我们就会在星球大气中烧毁
We're going to burn up in the atmosphere.
那快修复拨号装置
All right, so try to get the dhd working.
好让我们通过星门向基地求救
We can dial the gate, radio for help.
我试了
Well, i-i'll try,
可是无线电通讯也受影响中断了
But the radio communications are affected as well.
推进舱能源恢复
The drive pods are powering up.
但是问题是
But only one of them,
不是我干的
And it wasn't anything I did.
我是说  就这么一切正常了
I mean, it just came back on-line.
飞船它自己?
By itself?
有什么区别吗
It doesn't make any difference.
继续修复拨号装置
Keep working on that dhd.
我要尽力把大伙儿送回基地
I'll try to get us back in range.
好吧  我这儿有1个坏消息和1个好消息
Okay, I got bad news and I got good news.
说
What is it?
修复拨号装置的可能性微乎其微
Slim to no chance of getting the dhd working.
系统完全出问题了
The system is completely out of whack.
重新输送能源
It'll take some incredibly intricate
基本上是非常困难的
Rerouting of the power to--
好消息呢
Wh-- what's the good news?
这就是好消息啊
That was the good news.
坏消息是  我们失去了生命供给
The bad news is, we lost life support.
没多少氧气了
So no air?
是的
Right.
所以说是坏消息
That's why it's bad.
好吧  我们要过星门了
All right, we're back in range.
继续试着修复  这也许是唯一机会了
Just keep working on the dhd. this may be our last shot--
发生了什么
What just happened?
不知道  但是一切都恢复正常了
I don't know, but we're back online.
拨号装置?
Dhd?
所有一切!
Everything!
推进器  生命供给  什么都正常了
We got propulsion, life support, you name it.
亚特兰蒂斯  我是谢帕德
Atlantis, this is sheppard.
请打开星门通道
Coming in for approach,
但是我们系统出了点小问题
But our systems are a little whacked.
如果10秒中内我们还没通过
If we're not there in about 10 seconds,
派一艘飞船前来援助
Send a jumper for us.
收到  中校
Copy that, colonel.
别掉以轻心
Brace yourselves again.
其他飞船有类似情况不
Any of the other jumpers reporting trouble?
没有  很可能是偶然事件
No. probably an isolated incident,
但麦凯和泽兰卡会调查此事的
But mckay and zelenka are checking into it.
我们得停飞这艘飞船
We should probably ground the jumpers
直到查出问题出自何处
Till we know what the problem is, though.
好的  那个星球...
All right. but the planet--
适合阿尔法基地不
Suitable for an alpha site?
是的  很理想
Yeah. perfect.
除了有些猴子一样的生物
Well, except for the monkey-like creature
飞来飞去...
Flying around...
但我想我们能够搞定它
But I think we can handle that.
猴子?
Monkey?
麦凯有飞猴的照片  他会拿给你的
Yeah, mckay's got some photos. he'll show 'em to you.
你刚才说那猴子会飞?
Did you say "flying"?
弟兄们  进展的怎么样了
So, how's it going, boys?
修好了没
Did you get it fixed?
没毛病好修啊
There's nothing to fix.
什么
What?
我们做了电池测试
We ran a battery of tests.
飞船功能一切正常
The jumper's in perfect condition.
那怎么系统一下子全失灵了
How come the systems were all screwy?
你问对了
You got me.
叫我们怎么把那所谓的
We couldn't recreate
异常现象再表演一次
Any of the so-called anomalies.
十万个为什么先生  他也看到了
Hey, sammy skeptic, he saw it, too!
若楠和泰勒他们也看到了
As did ronon and teyla.
所有主能源供应系统失灵了
All of our primary systems went down.
好吧  我相信你
That's okay, I believe you.
别敷衍我
I don't think you do.
我想  之所以出现问题
I just that I think that maybe the problem
可能是你们无意中碰到了什么东西
Might've been caused by something you unwittingly--
我什么也没做  不管有意没意
I didn't do anything! wittingly or un.
好吧  你们继续
Okay, okay.
飞船什么故障也没有
There's nothing wrong with the jumper?
现在一切完好
Well, not anymore.
我想之前也没有什么故障
Well, I don't think there ever was anything--
适可而止哈
Okay, enough.
拜托
please.
总控室?  我是理查德·伍尔希
Control room? this is richard woolsey.
我走错了电梯  来到了...
I took a wrong turn in a transporter and ended up...
我不知道现在自己在哪里
I have no idea where I am.
电梯门打不开
But now the transporter door won't open.
能帮我确定我所处位置  并开启电梯门吗?
Can you locate me and open it, please?
有人吗?
Hello?
罗德尼?
Rodney?
请说
Go ahead.
你又在瞎玩总电源?
You messing around with the power again?
灯光闪烁不定
The lights are flickering.
没错  很多人都在向我抱怨
Yeah, I'm getting reports from all over the place.
有人吗?
Hello?
罗德尼...
Rodney...
你有没注意到...
Have you noticed the--
是的
Yes.
那你有没有...
Well, do you have any-
没有
not yet.
局部的?
Localized?
不  整个城市的能量都中断了
No. got power disruptions all over the city.
那零点装置呢?
Oh. zpm?
还在运转  能量充足
Still online, plenty of power.
突然就...
It's just suddenly become, uh--
...不稳定了
...unstable.
听起来就像你说的
Sounds not unlike what you said
和发生在飞船上的一样
Happened in the puddle jumper.
是的 很明显是一样
Yes. remarkably not unlike it.
异常情况波及到城市的系统了?
Perhaps the anomaly spread to the city's systems?
不可能
That's impossible.
在我们穿过星门之前
I disabled the network connection
我就已经断开了亚特兰蒂斯
Between the jumper and atlantis
和飞船之间的网络
Before we even came through the gate.
只是个巧合?
Coincidence, then?
你们在这  我用无线电找过你们
There you are! I tried to radio you--
是的  通讯系统瘫了
Yeah, well, communications are down.
没错  怎么样了
Yeah, obviously. what's up?
我们正在修复它
We're working on it.
什么?  我刚才差点又被
Well, I just almost got zapped
一连串闪电击了
By a bolt of lightning.
什么  位移电流?  在这?
What? displacement current? here?
没错  就在这  在那个走廊里
Yeah, right there, in the corridor.
和我们在飞船里碰到的一样
Just like the one we had in the jumper.
看来不是巧合了
So... not a coincidence.
星门流失能量
We just lost power to the stargate!
什么
What?
大概是一种病毒  自我上传过来
Well, maybe, like, a virus uploaded itself--
不  为了避免这些  我切断了
No, no, no, I disabled the jumper's
和飞船的网络连接
Network connection for this very reason.
所以这种异常不可能从
There's no way the anomaly
飞船传播到城市系统
Jumped to the city's systems.
你最好弄明白
You'd better figure it out...
现在不管在飞船上的是什么
Because whatever was in that jumper
它已经在这个城市了
Is now in this city.
你刚才去哪了
Where've you been?
城市的另一边
On the other side of the city.
电梯出了故障把我送到了东面码头
Transporter malfunctioned and sent me to the east pier.
我是自己走回来的
I had to walk all the way back.
整个城市的能源都中断了
We've got power disruptions all over the city.
几乎所有系统都受到了影响
Nearly every system is affected.
我想可能是飞船上的
We think whatever was wrong with the jumper
什么东西感染了城市系统
Has infected atlantis.
那只是其中一种可能性
It's one of several possibilities
我们正在找出来
We're looking into.
其中一种?
Several?
那只是可能
It's a possibility.
事实是  我们也不知道
All right? the point is, we have no idea
这里到底怎么了
What's going on here.
我差点被电光劈死
I was almost hit by a bolt of lightning.
欢迎加入倒霉蛋行列
Yeah. join the club.
能量形成后再被高压的
The energy builds up in one are and then discharges,
位移电流释放
In a high-voltage displacement current.
不稳定而且致命
Very erratic, very lethal.
我呼过你
I tried to radio you.
没错  但是通讯系统当掉了
Yeah, well, communications are also down.
星门也是
So is the stargate.
我们不能向地球拨号了?
We can't dial earth?
别担心  好吗
Don't worry. all right?
我会找出原因的
I will figure it out.
我运行了一些诊断程序  缩小和...
I just got to run a few diagnostics, narrow down and --
这可不妙
Well, that can't be good.
好吧
Okay. okay...
我们得组织一些小组
We, uh... we need to organize some teams,
分散到各个地点
Fan out through the city,
让所有人都保持镇定
Keep everyone calm
直到我们找出来究竟是...
Until we figure out exactly what the--
这笔记本自己启动了
The laptop just booted up.
可能里面有电池
Probably just the battery.
不  他是接到能源系统上的
No, no, no, it's drawing power from the system.
每样东西都停了  除了你的电脑?
So everything's out except your computer?
我和你一样糊涂
I'm as confused as you are.
那是什么
what is that?
像是什么代码
some like of code
也许是
may be
也有可能是信息
could be a message
求助?
help?
你是谁
who are you?
伊丽莎白·韦尔
elizabeth weir
韦尔博士
Dr. weir?
她已经死了
But she's dead.
我们是这么被告知的
So we've been told.
或许...
Perhaps...
你应该回应她
You should answer her.
对
Right.
你在哪里
where are you?
在计算机里
computer
在计算机里?
In the computer?
她怎么会在计算机里
How can she be in the computer?
现在情况很不好
difficult current conditon
发生什么事了
what happened to you?
亚空间...不好控制...正在试图...
subspace...difficult control...trying to...
是你弄的吗
Did you do that?
还在吗
are you still there?
帮帮我
help me
好了  罗德尼?
All right. rodney?
罗德尼  回话
Rodney, come in.
罗德尼  能听到吗
Rodney? can you hear me?
说吧
Go ahead.
我已经完成了升级程序
I've completed the patch.
等你准备好后就试试吧
Go ahead and try it. whenever you're ready.
好的  上帝保佑
Okay... fingers crossed.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
不管这个东西是什么
Well, whatever this entity is,
它完全压倒了我们的城市系统
It's completely overwhelming the city's systems.
如果摊开来看
It's spread out,
它有很多零碎的程序
Like dozens of fragmented programs
就是那些搞破坏的
That are fouling up
破坏能源管理系统  破坏通讯系统  随便什么
Power management, communications, you name it.
现在我把他们组合起来
Now, I've managed to merge them,
放入一个更大的程序里
To patch them together into one incredibly large program
那样一来可使我们的系统稍微稳定些
That will,A), hopefully render our systems slightly more stable,
二来可以让我们更好的
And, b), allow us to better communicate
和这个管它是什么东西的
With whoever or whatever it is
自称是韦尔博士的人交流
That's claiming to be dr. weir.
把所有程序整合起来
Isn't merging all these programs
不是有潜在危险吗
Potentially dangerous?
嗯  是的
Well, hell, yeah.
但是总比让这个东西
But it's no more dangerous than allowing this thing
继续大肆破坏城市系统来的强
To continue wreaking havoc on the city's systems.
还要算上被电劈死
Or getting zapped by bolts of lightning.
好的  我试着合成出
Okay, so, let's see if I can synthesize
一种适当频率的音频
A voice to communicate with.
用来和伊丽莎白交流
Elizabeth, if I make the proper calibrations,
她应该也能听到我们
She should be able to hear us too.
现在...
Now...
伊丽莎白?
Elizabeth?
罗德尼?
Rodney?
是不是就我觉得...或者
Is it just me,
这"伊丽莎白"听起来怎么有点不一样?
Or does, uh, "elizabeth" sound a little different?
我正在弄
I'm on it, I'm on it.
你是伊丽莎白·韦尔吗
Are you elizabeth weir?
是的  罗德尼  是我
Yes, rodney. it's me.
我尽量了
It's the best I can do.
我很抱歉引起这些麻烦
I'm sorry to cause all this trouble.
谁和你在一起   约翰·谢帕德在吗
Who's there with you? is john sheppard there?
我在
Hi.
能再听到你的声音真好
It's so good to hear your voice again.
我们...
We, uh...
都以为你...死了
Thought you were... dead.
我是的
I suppose I am.
我的肉体...是的
My... my physical body, anyway.
但是我的意识还很完整
But my consciousness is still intact.
是的  出什么事了
Right. so, um... what happened?
你记得那天
Do you remember the day I ordered you
我命令你离开  不要管我吗
To leave me behind?
约翰
John!
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth!
走
Go!
是的  我记得
Yeah... yeah, I remember.
在那之后
Well, after that,
复制人把我带到了一个实验室
The replicators took me to a lab.
我身体里的纳米细胞被释放了
The nanites in my body were unleashed
而且可以复制
And allowed to replicate.
我加入了复制人的行列  但是在新形态中
I joined the population, but even in my new form,
我原始的意识还保留了下来
My original consciousness was still there.
我还是我
I was still me.
我想把意识藏起来
I tried to hide it,
但是一些复制人还是能注意到
But a few of the others could sense it.
他们是纳姆的残存人员
They were remnants of niam's old group.
我相信你遇到了一些他们的作品
I believe you encountered some of their handiwork--
复制版本的我还有你和你的小组
Replicator-built human versions of me and your team.
你听说过这个  是吧
Hmm. you heard about that, did you?
他们死后我才知道的
Only after they were killed.
那另外的那个你  人类的...那个
Now, the other you, the human... one,
她认为你已经被消灭了
She thought you'd been destroyed.
那正是我们小队队长
That's what the leaders of our group
希望她相信的
Wanted her to believe.
为了安全起见  他们刻意使我们分开
They kept us apart deliberately,for security reasons.
这些都确实很有意思
This is all very interesting, I'm sure.
但是还不能解释
But none of it explains
你怎么会变成虚拟的声音
How you've come to be a disembodied voice
出现在我们的电脑系统里
In our computer system.
是...理查德·伍尔希吗
Is that... richard woolsey?
是的
Um, yes.
是我
it is.
我是新的...
I'm the, uh, the new--
新的指挥官
The new you.
我明白了
I see.
那么  发生什么事情了
So what-- what-- what happened?
你怎么会
How did you...
以这样的形态
End up...
来到这里?
In there?
我们在逃亡
We were on the run.
欧博罗斯和其他人千方百计的追捕我们
Oberoth and the others were hunting us down
因为他觉得我们信仰异教邪说
For our heretical beliefs.
因此  找到并消灭我们
It was only a matter of time
只是时间问题
Before we'd be captured and destroyed,
除非有奇迹出现
Unless something miraculous happened.
然而奇迹真的出现了
And something did.
我们的消息是正确的
Our intel was correct...
那个星球已经完全被摧毁了
The planet has been completely destroyed.
你能找到复制人的痕迹吗
Can you detect any trace replicator cells?
不能
Negative.
他们已经完全被消灭了
They've been completely wiped out.
好
Good...
我们终于可以心无旁骛地
We can finally get to work
开始我们的工作了
Without having to look over our shoulders.
是时候开始了...
It's time to begin...
那不是奇迹
Uh, well, that wasn't a miracle,
是我们干的
That was us.
我们摧毁了复制人的星球
We destroyed the replicator homeworld.
我知道
I know.
对你们  我们感激不尽
We owe you a debt of gratitude,
因为是你们  帮助我们
Because it allowed us
安心地追求我们的理想
To pursue our goal in peace.
你指"升天"?
You mean ascension?
对  泰勒
Exactly, teyla.
我们找到了合适的星球  接着开展工作
We found a suitable planet and began our work.
我尽可能的帮他们
I did what I could to help them.
我引导他们去冥想
I tried to lead them in meditation,
教他们如何"卸掉重负"
To teach them how to "release their burden,"
但是这很困难
But it was difficult.
我来猜猜  你们本身是机械体的问题
Let me guess-- you ran into a small hiccup
把你囧到了
With the fact that you're all machines?
是的
Yes.
我想说的是
Well, as much as I'd like to say
这不大可能
We didn't see that coming...
你知道的  我们以前试过的
We, you know, did.
我们中的一员  卡拉森
One of our group, koracen,
他认为  我们是科技的产物
Argued that it was a mistake
而回避这一点  是一种错误
To try and run away from our technological origin,
我们该利用这一点
That we should embrace it
从科技的角度来找到的解决方法
And find a technological solution.
我们知道复制人的意识可以数字化
We know that a replicator mind can be digitized
还可以在个体间转移
And transferred from one body to another.
我找到了一个方法
But I've discovered a way that will allow us
可以让我们以能量场的形式存在
To exist indefinitely as fields of energy...
有效的上传自身进入亚空间
Effectively uploading ourselves into subspace,
那么我们就可以自由的翱翔于这个星系
Where we'll be free to move about the galaxy
可以脱离我们的机械体
Unencumbered by physical existence.
那我们的身体怎么办
What would happen to our bodies?
像灰尘一样
The nanite bonds holding them together
四处飘散
Would be severed.
你的意思是  实体完全毁掉
You mean they'll be destroyed?
是的  因为我们已经不再需要
Yes, but we'll no longer need them.
卡拉森  假如不成功的话...
Koracen, if this doesn't work...
肯定会成功的
It will work.
你告诉过我们  成功的升天
You told us that ascension is achieved
是当身体被转化成纯粹的能量
When the physical body is transformed into pure energy.
我能做到这一点
I can make that happen for us.
一旦到了亚空间
Once in subspace,
没什么能阻挡我们
Nothing can prevent us
进入一个更高阶段的生存形式
From continuing on to the next plane of existence.
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
完成了
It's done.
机器升天?
Machine ascension?
然后并没有成功
Except it didn't work.
并没有下一个进程
There was no next step,
在任何一个感官的世界
No "ascension"
根本没有所谓的升天
In any meaningful sense of the word.
从那时起  我们就困在了亚空间
We've been stuck in subspace ever since.
那是什么感觉
What is it like?
不断的能量跃动
Oh... constant motion.
震耳欲聋的噪音
And deafening noise.
犹如难以想象的偏头痛
It's like the worst migraine you could possibly imagine.
我不知道
I don't know.
我的偏头痛很严重
I've had some pretty horrendous migraines--
我们开始在整个星系中寻找
We started searching the galaxy,
可以让我们重回实体的方法
Looking for a way to regain any kind of physical form.
我们去过
We came across
一些科技发达的国家...
A few other technologically advanced societies...
真的?  在这个星系里?
Really? in this galaxy?
你会惊讶  有这么多科技发达的社会
You'd be surprised how many more are out there,
藏在幽灵族的眼皮底下
Keeping themselves hidden from the wraith.
我们控制过许多电脑系统
We occupied various computer systems,
甚至短暂的控制了幽灵的系统
Even wraith tech for a short while.
幽灵系统?  真的?
Wraith tech? really?
那里非常不舒服
It was extremely unpleasant.
事实上  无论我们怎样呕心沥血
In fact, no matter where we looked,
我们都找不到哪种科技手段
We couldn't find any technology that would allow us to exist
能让我们象以前一样生活
As anything even remotely like what we were before.
这就是你来这里的原因
Which is why you came here.
你知道亚特兰蒂斯的电脑
You knew that atlantis's computers
拥有足够大的能量
Were big enough and powerful enough
来容纳你
To house your entire program.
其他一些古人
The others
变的很失落  而且变得充满仇恨
Were growing increasingly frustrated, and bitter.
我离开了他们
I broke away from them,
独自来找你们
And started looking for you on my own.
我在整个星系找了几个月
I searched the galaxy for months,
接着我找到你的飞船
And then I detected your puddle jumper
和它连接上了
And connected with it.
也险些把我们害死了
Nearly killing us in the process.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry for that.
我目前的状况
My current condition
很不稳定  很难自控
Is extremely volatile, difficult to control.
尤其在开始的阶段
Especially during the initial moments,
尝试融入新系统的时候
Trying to interface with new tech.
但是我不知道还能去哪里
But I didn't know where else to turn.
你们是我唯一的朋友
You're the only friends I have.
别问我  这是个骗局
You ask me, it's a trick.
有人在冒充韦尔博士
Someone just pretending to be dr. weir.
那万一是她呢
But what if it is her?
我们还有古人的机器
We still have the ancient machine I used
我曾经用它来制造弗兰
To build fran.
我能不费吹灰之力造出复制人....
I could easily build another replicator to--
不
No!
我有后门程序  自杀按钮
I'd put in failsafes, a kill switch.
听着  我的意思是
Look, what I'm saying is,
我所掌握的先进技术....
That with all the advancements I've been able to make--
为你所掌握的先进技术感到骄傲
With all due respect to the advancements you've made,
但是  有一件事情永远不变
One thing remains constant--
复制人过于强大
Replicators are far too powerful
我们一点都不该信任他们
To even think about trusting them.
他们已经是2个星系的罪魁祸首了
They've been the scourge of two galaxies.
你比我更清楚
You know better than anyone
消灭他们更是难上加难
How difficult it was to get rid of them.
那我们拿她怎么办
Then what should we do with her?
她不能呆在这里
Well, she can't stay where she is.
她会让我们的电脑崩溃的
She's frying the city's computers.
也许我们可以把她或者它
Well, maybe we can upload her--
随便怎么称呼
Or it or whatever this thing is--
上传送进虚拟世界
Into a virtual reality,
就像我们处理艾娃一样?
Like we did with ava?
也许能行  但也很困难啊
That could work, but it wouldn't be easy,
尤其是她不想离开
Especially if she doesn't want to go.
我们可以和她沟通啊
We'll... talk to her.
罗德尼  我们刚检测到在南码头实验室
Rodney, we just detected anomalous energy levels
有异常的能量跃动
In the south pier lab.
复制人制造器
The replicator machine.
她在给自己制造身体
She's building herself a body.
她一定是在数据库里找到的
She must've found it in the database.
切断那个地方的电源
Shut down power to that room.
我试过了
I-i tried.
我甚至用无线遥控来切断
I've also tried to radio down there,
但无线不能用
But communications are still offline.
发生什么了
What's going on?
门被重重关上了
Door slammed shut.
打不开
Can't get it open.
好  让开
okay, move!
呼救支援  带一些重武器过来
Go get some back-up, some heavy arms,
封锁这里的所有走廊
And cover every corridor out of here.
带些C4炸弹  我们要炸开这个门
Get some c4. we'll have to blast this door.
不行  控制板很烫
No, panel is toast.
还有其他入口吗
Is there another door we can access?
大家好
Hello.
听我说  我是伊丽莎白·韦尔
Listen to me-- I'm elizabeth weir.
她明显是着急了
Obviously she was in a hurry,
就使用了存在机器中的
She just used the previous replicator template
先前的复制人模板
That was already in the machine,
是弗兰
Which was fran.
约翰  我对你们没有恶意
John, I'm not a threat to you.
不管你是什么
Well, whatever you are,
我得说  重建了一具复制人的躯体
I'd say building a replicator body
算是个相当大的威胁
Is a pretty big threat.
伊丽莎白·韦尔决不会干这种事
Elizabeth weir would never do such a thing.
机器已经关闭
Okay... the machine is deactivated.
远离控制晶体
Removed the control crystal,
这样没有人能继续制造出更多的复制人
Which means no one will be building any more replicators.
相信我  我和你们一样疑虑
Believe me, I was just as concerned
我这么做究竟对不对
About doing this as you.
不过罗德尼对这项技术
But the adjustments rodney's made
所作的调整  消除了一切危险性
To this technology eliminate any danger.
我不能复制
I can't replicate,
当我的意识开始控制这副躯体
And since my consciousness is controlling this body,
我真的相信
I truly believe--
你的意识
Your consciousness?
无意冒犯  但我还没完全信服
No offense, but I'm not completely sold
你自诩的身份
On your being who you say you are.
我也不信
That makes two of us.
我理解你们对我的怀疑
I understand your skepticism,
但我的确是伊丽莎白·韦尔
But I am elizabeth weir.
但愿我有办法向你们证实
I wish there was some way I could prove it to you.
那可难了
That'll be difficult.
复制人俘获韦尔博士之后
Any personal information or memories
任何私人信息和记忆
Could have easily been mined
都可以从她的意识中
From dr. weir's consciousness
轻易获取
When the replicators captured her.
我知道
I know.
所以让我先提供些有价值的东西以示诚意
At least let me start by offering something of value.
我们洗耳恭听
Let's hear it.
我们变型之后
The technical specs
所寄居过的几个系统的
Of several of the systems we've inhabited
技术资料
Since our transformation...
包括幽灵人的技术
Including wraith tech--
我已经上传到你们的计算机上了
I've already uploaded them to your computer.
真的吗
Really?
那...太好了
Well, that's... great.
我只要求你们
All I ask
给我一个机会
Is that you give me a chance
来赢得你们信任
To earn your trust.
我决不会做任何事去伤害你们
I would never, ever, do anything to harm any of you,
还有亚特兰蒂斯
Or atlantis.
现在有个好消息
Well, the good news is that now
她将自己载入了复制人躯体
She's downloaded herself into the replicator's body,
这就不会损坏亚特兰蒂斯的计算机
She's not screwing up atlantis' computers.
电力稳定  星门运行正常
The power's stable, the gate's working,
电脑通信也重新连接上了
And communications are back online.
你确定她不能自我复制吗
You're sure she can't replicate on her own?
确定
Positive.
我是说每项安全措施都是她设定的
I mean, she instituted every safeguard.
如果我们把她送到一个安全地点
If we move her to a secure location,
那么我想
Then I think--
等一下  你不是在建议我
Wait a minute! you're not suggesting
欣然接受把她留在这儿的想法吧
That I entertain the notion of keeping her here?
我只是在说
I'm just saying that
要是我们一直把她留在眼皮底下
If we keep her under constant guard,
可以将她的威胁控制在最小
It'll minimize any threat she poses--
万一她真有恶意的话
If she even poses a threat.
而且还给了我们更多时间来研究她
And it'll give us more time to study her.
来者
That thing in there...
是一个复制人
Is a replicator.
即便密切监控
There are far too many ways this can go wrong,
还是会防不胜防
Even if she's kept under constant guard.
所有人都质疑我制造的第一个弗兰
Everyone doubted the first fran I built,
而后来发现她极其安全
And she turned out to be perfectly safe
极其可靠
And perfectly reliable.
没错  你造出过弗兰
That's right-- you built fran.
她的意识也是你创造的
You created her consciousness.
如今你想相信这个新弗兰
Now, as much as you want to believe that this new fran
真的是韦尔博士
Is indeed dr. weir,
我们可没那么大把握
We cannot be certain of that.
据我们的经验
For all we know,
没准是欧博罗斯借茧作俑
It could be oberoth inside that body.
好瘆人
That's creepy.
要是它就是韦尔博士呢
What if it is dr. weir?
这是我的错
Look, this is my fault.
是我激活了伊丽莎白体内的纳米细胞
I'm the one who reactivated the nanites in elizabeth.
尽管是为了救她
True, to save her, but...
但麻烦都是我造成的
I'm the one who created this mess.
我想解铃还须系铃人吧
I think I should be the one to, you know, fix it.
我欠伊丽莎白的
I owe it to elizabeth.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry...
太危险了
But it's too dangerous.
我看我们还是按照原计划
I say we stick with our original plan--
将她的意识上传到虚拟世界
Upload her consciousness into a virtual reality.
让她在那儿证明自己
Let her prove herself there,
在那里她也不会造成什么威胁
Where she can't do any damage.
有孩子了
A child?
泰勒
Oh, teyla...
我真为你高兴
I'm so happy for you.
是男孩还是
Uh, is it a boy, or...
男孩
Boy.
叫什么名字
What's his name?
图门·约翰·艾玛根
Torren John emmagan.
图门是你父亲的名字
Torren, for your father.
那么约翰
And, uh, john...
是谢帕德中校
Colonel sheppard?
是的
Yes.
等等  你是说约翰·谢帕德是
Wait, you're not saying john sheppard is--
不
No.
不是
No...
孩子父亲是阿托斯星人
The father is athosian.
我来猜猜  是迦楠
Let me guess... kanaan?
对呀  你怎么知道
Yes. how did you...
每次你说起这位"朋友"
Every time you spoke of him, this "friend,"
你的眼睛里总是闪着光彩
There was always a sparkle in your eyes.
那么孩子和你一起在亚特兰蒂斯吗
So, is the baby here with you in atlantis?
不
No.
他和他爸爸在一起
He is with his father.
在其他地方
Off-world.
抱歉打扰一下
Sorry to interrupt.
没关系
No, it's all right.
我们谈得差不多了
We were just finishing.
这些...不好意思了
Sorry about all this.
没事  我理解
It's okay, I understand.
刚听到泰勒的喜事
Amazing news about teyla.
听着
Um, look...
我们都想相信
We all want to believe
你说的话
You are who you say you are.
我明白
I understand that you...
你们必须小心谨慎
You have to be cautious,
但真的是我  约翰
But it really is me, john.
你只需给我时间
You just have to give me time.
你会看到
You'll see that--
哦不
Oh, no...
怎么了
What's wrong?
他们发现我了
They've found me.
谁
Who?
其他复制人
The other replicators.
他们正向亚特兰蒂斯赶来
They're on their way to atlantis.
来了多少人
How many are coming?
8个
Eight of them.
早知道她会干出什么好事
And we saw what kind of damage one could do...
我们要不要启动零点装置
Should we pull the zpm?
那是最后的杀手锏  我们还没到那份上
That's a last resort. we're not there yet.
并且我还需要它
Meanwhile, I'll need it
帮助实施我能想出的对策
To effect any counter-measures I can come up with.
他们多久能到
How soon will they get here?
几分钟吧
Well, minutes, if that.
我们能做些什么来保护我们的城市么
Is there anything we can do to protect the city?
你能不能竖起防火墙之类的
Can you put up some kind of firewall?
防火墙不顶用
A firewall won't work.
你阻挡不了他们
You can't block them,
他们在亚空间中来去自如
They just pop in and out of subspace.
到处都是  无法预料
They're here, they're there, it's impossible to predict.
我可以编一个程序
I could write a program that immediately quarantines
即时隔离系统中非正常运行的程序
Any anomalous behavior in the system,
类似杀毒软件的东西
Like an anti-virus software.
但是得花点时间
It's going to take some time, though.
尽你所能吧
Just do what you can.
把弗兰  韦尔博士  不管她是谁
Keep fran, dr. weir, whoever she is--
监控起来
Under guard.
暂时先不把她的意识上传到虚拟世界
We won't upload her to the vr just yet.
也许还需要她帮忙解决问题
We may need her help dealing with them.
你骗了我们
You set us up.
不!  我真的以为我已经和他们断绝了联系
No! I honestly believed I had broken away
他们追踪不到我的
Without them being able to track me.
告诉他们离亚特兰蒂斯远点
Tell them to stay away from atlantis.
我会试试  不过近点会更容易(交流)
I'll try, but it'll get easier as they get closer.
听我说  我确信他们并不想伤害任何人
Look, I'm sure they don't intend to hurt anyone.
你告诉他们继续走  到其他地方去
You tell them to keep moving, go someplace else.
他可以去...
It might go a----
谢帕德
Sheppard!
说吧  罗德尼
Go ahead, Rodney.
他到了
...it arrived...
无法...运行系统...
Wasn't able... program the system...
罗德尼?
Rodney?
他们的混合力量
Their combined force
完全冲破了主能源网
Is completely overwhelming the main power grid!
谢帕德
Sheppard!
他们来了?
They're here?
共八人  在攻击城市的电脑
All eight of 'em, slamming the city's computers!
"杀毒"程序呢
What about the anti-virus program?
都没时间完成
Didn't have time to finish it!
行了  那可能都没用
Look, it probably wouldn't have worked anyway.
瑞迪克  我要你开启零点装置
Radek, I need you to pull the zpm,
关闭所有必要的naquadah发电机
Power down all essential naquadah generators.
瑞迪克
Radek!
信号又差了
Communications are down again!
罗德尼
Rodney!
罗德尼  我正要转换能源
Rodney, I'm trying to divert power,
但它现在太不稳定了
But it's become far too unstable.
是不是先开零点装置
Perhaps now we should pull the zpm?
罗德尼?
Rodney?
我们走  打开零点装置
Let's-- let's go-- pull the zpm.
除了主动力其他都关了
Shut down all power except for the main power.
我的天啊
Oh, god.
他死了
He's dead.
我们联系上了
We've established contact
一个叫卡拉森的复制人
With the replicator known as Koracen.
他说是代表其他人来谈话的
He claims to speak on the others' behalf.
卡拉森?  我是伊丽莎白·韦尔
Koracen? It's Elizabeth Weir.
伊丽莎白?  我们很担心你
Elizabeth? We were worried about you.
听我说
Listen to me.
你们要离开这儿
You need to leave this place.
你们造成了太多伤害
You're causing a lot of harm.
我们会离开的
We will leave.
但我们要先拿到身体  就像你
But first we wish to be given bodies, as you have.
我们早就告诉过你那不可能
We've already told you that's out of the question.
但伊丽莎白已经拿到了一个
And yet Elizabeth has been given one.
我们当时别无选择  而我们也不打算
It wasn't our choice, and we're not planning on
让她继续用这身体
Letting her keep it.
我们并不想伤害任何人
We do not wish to harm anyone.
但我们的一个朋友已经死了
One of our guys is already dead,
收回你那"我们是友好的"废话
So you can save your "we come in peace" crap!
卡拉森  求你了
Koracen, please.
离开这座城市  让我来和他们谈
Just leave the city and let me negotiate with them.
我们肯定会找出
I'm sure we can figure out
能帮助你的方法
Some way to help you.
帮我的方法就是
The way to help us is by
替换了古人机器中的控制晶体
Replacing the control crystal in the ancient machine
那我们就能重造复制体了
So that we may build replicator bodies.
这是你要做的
That is what you will do.
如果我们不答应呢
And if we don't?
卡拉森?
Koracen?
情况不妙
Not good. Not good!
门又关上了
Aw, gate's down again!
我们无法控制城市
We're losing control of the city.
他们关了飞船的舱门
They just shut the jumper bay doors!
他们想阻止我们离开
They're trying to keep us from leaving.
不能破除指令么
Can't you override it?
我被阻在外面了
I'm locked out!
不会吧
Oh, no.
他们还入侵了零点装置
They just engaged the zpm.
能量级上升得很快
Energy levels are rising rapidly!
他们这是要干吗
Why, what are they doing?
他们要沉了这城市
They're sinking the city.
打开防护罩
Raise the shield.
已经被他们破坏了
They've disabled it.
有什么主意了没
Any ideas?
没有  我们在下沉
No, we're going down.
水已经没过
Water's already cresting
外码头较低的甲板了
The lower decks of the outer piers.
它随时可能冲击城市通道
It's going to breach the city corridors any second now.
我想你帮我传个信
I want you to send them a message for me.
我正试着和他们沟通
I've been trying to communicate with them,
让他们停下
Telling them to stop.
他们不会听我的
They won't listen to me.
我要说的不是这些
That's not what I want to tell them.
不是?
It's not?
告诉他们...继续
Tell them... to go ahead.
沉了这城市吧
Sink the city.
毁了他们获得机械体的
Destroy their only chance of ever regaining
唯一机会
Any kind of physical form.
你们已经找遍了整个星系
You've searched the entire galaxy.
你们知道复制人的家园已经不复存在
You know the replicator homeworld was destroyed.
唯一剩下的
The only place remaining
有技术能力帮助你们达到目的的
With the technology you need to achieve your goals
就只有这里
Is right here.
所以继续啊  毁了它吧
So go ahead, destroy it.
然后永生困在中间地带
Stay trapped in limbo forever.
南码头的一级已经完全没入水中
Level one of the south pier is completely under water.
他们不会停了
They won't stop.
好吧
Fine.
那我们就一起死吧
Then we'll all die together.
他们逐渐退出零点装置
They're powering down the zpm!
城市在趋于稳定
The city's stabilizing.
好了
All right.
我们可以来谈谈了
Now we can negotiate.
我有个建议
I have a proposal.
我已经和其他人沟通过了
I've already communicated it to the others,
也说服了他们达成一致
And convinced them to agree to it.
那我们来听听
Let's hear it.
人类的身体
Human bodies,
通过纳米技术制造
Nanite-manufactured,
但也有血有肉
But consisting of flesh and blood.
就像另一个伊丽莎白·韦尔
Like the other Elizabeth Weir
你们遇到的那个
You once encountered.
我们没有这种技术
We don't have that kind of technology here.
但我们有
But we do.
如果你们能提供临时的复制体
If you give us temporary replicator bodies,
和一个可用的实验室
And a lab to work in,
我们能够自己装配
We can assemble them ourselves.
什么  你要从复制体
What, you'll transfer your consciousness
转移意识到人体?
From the replicator body to the human body?
完全正确  作为人类
Exactly. as human beings,
我们和其他人一样
We would be every bit as vulnerable
容易受伤
As anyone else.
我们要吃要睡  会生老病死
We would eat, sleep, get sick... and die.
特别是老了时
Preferably of old age.
那升天呢
What about ascension?
我以为那还是列在你们的日程上
I'm assuming that's still on the agenda?
是的
It is.
等等  造一个人体
Wait a second. building humans--
那需要花时间对不对
That's going to take time, isn't it?
我是说  首先你们要发明
I mean, first, you've got to create
这种技术
The technology to do it...
我们说的是纳米技术
We're talking nanites--
一般来说  配置一个身体
I mean, organically assembling each body,
从内到外  都要从分子层开始
Inside out, starting at the molecular level.
然后还要做一个
Then you have to create the machine
传送意识的机器
To transfer the consciousness.
天知道这要多久
I mean, that's going to take god knows how long?
复制人工作起来很快
Replicators, as you know, work very fast.
不用休息吃饭或是睡觉
No need for breaks, or food, or sleep.
这可以考虑
It's worth thinking about.
他可能是对的
He may be right.
只要能重新控制了城市
I mean, if only to regain control of the city.
如果他们还在我们的电脑系统中
While they're in our computer systems,
亚特兰蒂斯就很危险
Atlantis is in serious trouble.
如果我们同意这么做
If we do this,
我希望对他们的能力有严格的限制
I want severe restrictions placed on their capabilities--
不能复制  不能变形
No replicating, no shape-shifting--
最基础的模式  这你放心
The basic model, you got it.
我是说  不能有附加的能力
I mean, no bells, no whistles.
他们可以做些小的修复
They'll be able to affect some minor repairs,
但仅此而已
But that's about it.
把实验室锁起来
Seal off the lab,
然后加个力场在周围
Put a force field around it,
你们觉得怎么安全就怎么做
Do whatever you need to do to feel safe.
我已经说服他们
But I've already convinced the others
那是他们的唯一选择了
That this is their only option.
他们不会给你们制造麻烦的
They won't give you any trouble.
我向你们保证
You have my word.
批准
Do it.
力场初始化
Okay, initializing force field.
你们的组员都准备就绪了吗
Are your teams in place?
日夜不断地监视
Around-the-clock watch.
很好
Good.
一旦人类的肉体被制造出来
Once these human bodies are made,
他们形神合一之后
And they're downloaded into them...
然后呢
What happens then?
鉴于他们和真正的人类
Seeing as they'll be just like
没什么两样
Any other human beings,
我觉得没有理由不放他们走
I see no reason not to let them go.
他们可以成为我们有利的盟友
They could become valuable allies.
如果他们当中  有的人拒绝形神合一怎么办
Well, what if one of 'em decides to stay?
我们还是一步一步来吧  好吗
Let's cross one bridge at a time, all right?
进行得怎样
How's it going?
快要完成了
Almost done.
正在制造最后一个人体
Just finishing up the last one.
进度神速啊
That was fast.
事实上  制造复制人易如反掌
Well, actually, creating replicators is fairly simple,
相对来说
Comparatively speaking.
人类  就不尽其然
Humans, not so much.
越早完成  就越好
Well, the sooner they get it done,the better.
当传输完成的时候
And once the last transfer is complete,
把复制人的身体全部销掉
I want those replicator bodies destroyed.
他们真是快马加鞭  不是吗
They certainly don't waste any time, do they?
是的  真是快
No, they don't.
没有间断  没有闲聊
There's no breaks, no chit-chat,
也没有交流行为
No social interaction whatsoever.
整个过程都全神贯注
Just the perfect working environment.
若楠
Ronon,
你不必整个过程都待在这
You don't have to stay there the whole time, you know.
我没事
I'm good.
他就整天在那唠唠叨叨
Talk, talk, talk, that's all he does.
也没办法让他住嘴
You can't shut him up.
有情况  随时通知我
Keep me apprised.
麦凯  能源被切断了
Mckay! power's out!
什么...力场!
What the-- force field!
发生什么事了
what happened?
一个复制人逃跑了
one of the replicators escaped,the causing
逃跑者早就密谋着进行某种计划
the leaper was working on some kind of hidden program
他趁着意识重回实体
and it was time to kill power
需要切断电源的时候
as soon as they were downloading replicators' bodies
那时候  力场停止运作
It disabled the force field,
这样一来  他们就可以打开大门  趁机逃跑
They were able to pry open the doors.
她在哪
Where is she?
她去追卡拉森去了
She went after koracen.
已有3个小队在外追捕他
Three teams are in pursuit.
所有无线电通讯系统瘫痪
We've lost all radio contact.
去支援他们吧
Go join 'em.
到指挥室去
Go up to the control room,
看能不能重启电源
And try to get the power restored.
他们怎么办
What do we do with them?
开枪
Shoot 'em.
一直开
Keep shooting.
直到他们倒下为止
They'll go down eventually.
慢着
Wait!
我们对卡拉森的计划一无所知
We knew nothing of koracen's plan.
如果我们和他同流合污
If we were a part of it,
我们现在就不会站在这里了
We would not be standing here right now.
拜托了
Please?
我们会按照你的吩咐做
We're complying with your wishes.
确保没有人可以走出这扇门
Nothing gets through that door.
只要他们动了一点点
If they move an inch...
就开枪
Shoot 'em.
慢着
Hold on!
等不及让意识回到人类的身体的时候了吧
You just couldn't wait for those human bodies,
是吗
Could you?
人类的身体是那样的脆弱  渺小
The human body is frail, weak...
每过一秒  都在向死亡迈前一步
Every second, that much closer to dying.
那关于升天的事
Yeah, and this whole ascension thing--
你也放弃了吗
You're just giving up on that? huh?
才不
Not at all.
肯定有别的方法可以做到
I'm certain there's another way.
拥有了这个身躯
With this body,
我有无穷的时间
I'll have plenty of time
去探索它
To discover it.
有什么进展
Any luck?
他们几乎关闭了所有的系统
They've shut just about everything down.
尤其是一些重要的系统
Power's cut to most of the critical systems.
除了星门拨号系统
Except for the dhd and the gate.
很明显  他们想利用星门拨号逃跑
They're obviously going to try to dial out.
现在  我修复了主机的远程控制功能
Now, I've managed to gain remote access to the mainframe.
我建立了一个周边工作区
I'm creating a workaround
来修复中心塔主要系统的
To allow the resumption of naquadah power
naquadah能源
To the central tower's primary systems.
虽然只是最少限度修复
Minimal, to be sure, but from there--
但是却可以覆盖复制人写的程序
...over-write the replicator program
和重启剩下的系统
And restart the remaining systems.
正是
Exactly.
加快吧  现在需要恢复能源
Just hurry. we need power back now.
好的  有什么东西我可以帮忙的吗
Okay, is there anything you want me to do?
有的  对新手来说  你可以
Yes, for starters, you could, um,
站到一边去
Stay out of my way.
好的  好的
Oh. yes. okay. fine.
还有闭上嘴
And be quiet.
站住!
Stop!
约翰  别过来
John, stay back.
让我来处理吧
Let me handle this.
难道你干的好事还不够多吗
Haven't you done enough already?
我只是想帮忙
I'm trying to help you.
怎么帮  逃跑吗?
By what? escaping?
我不知道卡拉森会这样做的
I didn't know that koracen would do this.
她当然知道
Of course she knew!
伊丽莎白由始至终
Elizabeth has been a willing participant
都很乐意加入我们的大计
In our goals from the very beginning.
混到这里来还是她的主意呢
It was her idea to come here in the first place.
你说过你已经和他们断绝联系了
You said you broke off from them,
他们已经不能跟踪你了
That they couldn't track you.
跟踪她?
Track her?
还是她提醒我们的
She was the one who alerted us
告诉我们时机成熟了的
When the time was right to come.
我们只是按她的吩咐办事
We were only following her commands.
约翰  听我说
John, listen to me.
我一定得把他们带来
I had to bring them here.
这是我们唯一的办法
It was our only chance...
唯一机会了
Our only way out.
我不知道卡拉森
I didn't know that koracen
会造成这样的麻烦
Would cause this kind of trouble.
我没有想过要伤害任何人
I didn't think that anyone would get hurt.
那你认为  我们该怎么做呢
What did you think we were going to do?
把复制人的身体都给你
Just give you a bunch of replicator bodies
然后再欢送你走吗
And send you on your way?
我深信  我们并不是你们的威胁
I truly believed that we were no threat to you.
你认为自己还是伊丽莎白
You may still think you're elizabeth,
但你已经不是了
But you're not.
如果你想继续未完的工作
If you'd like to resume your work,
我会批准的
I've decided to allow it.
当然  我们会重新开启力场
We would re-engage the force field, of course.
加强保安系统
Beef up security.
我太冒险了
It's too risky.
我原以为带他们来这里
I thought that bringing the others here
是万无一失的
Would be safe.
我错了
I was wrong.
我不能再担保
I can no longer guarantee
他们会不会再制造别的麻烦
There won't be any more trouble from them.
包括我自己
Or even myself.
那好吧
All right, um...
你有什么打算呢
What do you want to do?
我记得在你重新激活我体内的纳米细胞之后
I remember, after you reactivated the nanite cells inside me,
我说这个主意糟透了
I said this was a bad idea.
从此之后  所有事都乱套了
So much has gone wrong since then.
但我知道怎样去收拾残局
But I think I know how I can finally set things right.
继续吧
Go ahead.
如果你需要什么帮助
If you need anything else for your work,
告诉我们吧
Let us know.
谢谢  罗德尼
Thanks, rodney.
你必须再一次向我保证
Once again, you have to promise
在造好人类身体之前
To stay put until you're finished
不能去其他地方
Constructing the human bodies.
不离开你的家园
No leaving your homeworld,
不和亚特兰蒂斯以外的
No communication with any other civilization
任何外界联系
Except atlantis.
我向你保证
You have my word.
希望你的工作一直顺利  理查德
Good luck with your command, richard.
亚特兰蒂斯能由你这位能者管理  我很欣慰
It's comforting to know atlantis is in capable hands.
谢谢
Thank you.
启程吧
Shall we?
没事的
It's okay.
我先来吧
I'll go first.
证实安全
It's safe.
你确定重新设置激活程序有用吗
You're sure the dhd reconfiguration worked?
是的
Yes.
他们被送进空间之门去了
They were sent to a space gate.
我想这能够告诉我们她是否真的是伊丽莎白
I guess that answers the question as to whether it was really elizabeth?